Finding Aid for the Kenneth Macgowan Papers LSC.0887
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Involvement with Little Theatres, ca. 1920-1930
  - Material re Eugene O'Neill
    - Material re Kenneth Macgowan's lectures on Eugene O'Neill. v.p., 1928-1961.; Approximately 50 items. Typescript (some carbon) and printed. (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Included is correspondence, plus manuscripts, schedules, clippings, and other items re Mr. Macgowan's various lectures about Eugene O'Neill, touching also, on other subjects re the theater.
      Much of the material is grouped according to the place of the lectures.
    - Two screens and a stage; a lecture about Eugene O'Neill. Los Angeles, 1961.; 9 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 27, Folder 6)
      Included are 3 copies of the lecture, plus announcements, and miscellaneous notes.
    - Miscellaneous material re Eugene O'Neill, v.p., v.d.; 29 items. Holograph and printed items. (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Included is a letter to Kenneth Macgowan, an I.O.U., and many clippings, mailers, etc., re Eugene O'Neill and his works.
  - Various Items re Productions of Plays by Eugene O'Neill
    - Ephemera re various plays by Eugene O'Neill. v.p., v.d.; 7 items. Printed material. Items are alphabetically arranged. (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Included are mostly clippings referring to Anna Christie, The Emperor Jones, and The Hairy Ape.
    - Clippings re All Gods Chillum Got Wings. v.p., 1924.; 36 items. Printed material, plus 1 black and white photograph. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Ephemera re Beyond The Horizon. v.p., v.d.; 24 items. Printed material. (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Including clippings, theater programs, and copies of box office statements.
    - Material re Desire Under The Elms. v.p., v.d.; 40 items. Manuscript, typescript (some carbon) and printed material. (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Included are clippings, theater programs, advertisements, notes, typed quotations from reviews, lists of acting contracts, and 3 color posters, plus 1 letter from Sidney Howard to Mr. Macgowan, about the play.
    - Material re Fountain. New York, 1925.; 11 items. Typescript (carbon) and printed. (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Included are clippings, a playbill, and a cast list.
    - Material re the Great God Brown. v.p., 1926.; 18 items. Few typescript (some carbon), and printed material. (Box 27, Folder 13)
      Included are clippings, theater programs, and few miscellaneous letters, plus salary list.
    - Material re Lazarus Laughed. v.p., 1926-1928.; 28 items. Holograph, few typescript, and some printed material. (Box 27, Folder 14)
      Includes correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and the American Play Co., and with Marian Gering of the Chicago Play Producing Company, 2 copies of an agreement between The Actors'Theatre Incorporated, and Eugene O'Neill concerning the play, plus other lists and printed ephemera.
    - Letters to Kenneth Macgowan from Arthur Bissell, president of the Chicago Play Producing Company re Lazarus Laughed, and other O'Neill plays. Chicago, 1925-1927.; 17 items. Typescript and teletype. (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper clippings re Welded. v.p., February-March 15, 1924.; 82 items. (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper clippings re Welded, continued. v.p., March 16-April 1924.; 91 items. (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous material re Welded. New York, 1924.; 29 items. Typescript (mostly carbon), and some printed material. (Box 27, Folder 18)
      Included are box office statements, theater programs, and a few business letters.
- Motion Picture Production Files
  - Production Files of Various Motion Pictures Kenneth Macgowan Produced or Was Associated With
    - Alexander Graham Bell, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation
      - Correspondence re the motion picture. v.p., 1938-1939.; 67 leaves. Typescript (some carbon), teletype, and a few printed items. Items are alphabetically arranged. (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Ephemera, advertising material for the motion picture. v.p., 1938-1939.; 7 items. (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Ephemera, clippings re the motion picture. v.p., 1938-1939.; 34 items. (Box 28, Folder 3)
        Some research material is included.
      - Miscellaneous production records, financial statements, and various other material. [Hollywood], 1938-1939.; 7 items. (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Photographs of scenes, and photocopies of drawings for sets and scenes, plus a research photograph and notes, for the motion picture. [Hollywood], 1938.; 82 items. Black and white, size 8 × 10. (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Picture estimate. Los Angeles, 1939.; 21 sheets, fastened in a blue-green paper cover. Photocopy. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Research material, pamphlets. v.p., v.d.; 4 items. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Brigham Young, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation
      - Correspondence and reports re the motion picture. v.p., 1939-1940.; 55 leaves. Typescript (some carbon). Items are arranged chronologically. (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Ephemera, clippings from newspapers and periodicals, and advertising material for the motion picture. v.p., 1940.; 13 items. (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Picture estimate. Los Angeles, 1940.; 23 sheets, fastened in a green paper cover. Photocopy. (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Easy Come, Easy Go, Paramount Pictures, Incorporated
      - Production budget. Hollywood, 1945.; 28 sheets, fastened in a blue paper cover. Photocopy. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Edwin Booth, original treatment and synopsis for the motion picture, by Anne Herendeen. n.p., 1938.; 20 leaves. Typescript. Fastened in a folder (Not known if actually used). (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Four Men And A Prayer, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation
      - Miscellaneous material. v.p., 1938.; 7 items. Printed and photocopy. (Box 28, Folder 13)
        Including related clippings from newspapers and periodicals, and the Picture Estimate for the film.
      - Photographs of scenes from the motion picture. v.p. [?], 1935-1936.; 25 items. Glossy, black and white, size 8 × 10. (Box 28, Folder 14)
        Missing 10/26/88 D.S.Z.
    - Half Angel, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation
      - Miscellaneous material re the film. v.p., 1935-1936.; 25 items. Typescript (some carbon), printed and photograph. (Box 28, Folder 15)
        Including a few letters, various papers, plus a few clippings, and 7 black and white, glossy, photographs of scenes from the motion picture.
    - Happy Land, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation
      - Miscellaneous material re the film. v.p., 1943.; 25 items. Typescript (some carbon) and printed material. (Box 29, Folder 1)
        Including some correspondence, various papers, and some ephemera.
        - Anderson, Charles E., 3 items. (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Benchley, Robert C., 2 items. (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Kantor, MacKinlay., 5 items. (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Pichel, Irving., 3 items. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Picture estimate. Los Angeles, 1943.; 17 sheets, fastened in a green cover. Photocopy. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Hudson's Bay Company, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation
      - Miscellaneous material re the motion picture. v.p., 1940.; 49 items. Typescript (much carbon), printed and photocopy. (Box 29, Folder 3)
        Including inter-office correspondence of the studio, correspondence re Grace Lee Nute and with Grace Lee Nute, plus various records and ephemera.
      - Research material, information about the founding of the company, and Pierre Radisson. n.p., 1940.; 33 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Raleigh of Virginia, story outline for the motion picture, by Captain Lloyd Morris. n.p., September 25, 1937.; 7 leaves. Typescript, with corrections, filed in a blue paper cover. Not known if used, or followed through.
    - Rebel Yell, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation. n.p., 1943-1944.; 65 leaves. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Story outline for the motion picture, by Margaret Orussing and Albert Shelby LeVino, plus a previously written original story idea by Gerald Drayson Adams, plus some extra leaves of outline material.
    - The Return of Frank James, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation. [Hollywood], 1939-1940.; 23 items. Typescript (some carbon), printed and photograph. (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Material re the motion picture, including some correspondence, studio conference records, black and white photos of scenes, a few clippings, and production budget sheets.
    - The Return of the Cisco Kid, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation. [Hollywood], 1939.; 23 items. Typescript, mimeograph, printed, and photograph. (Box 29, Folder 8)
      Material re the motion picture, including production reports, various records, a few clippings, and black and white photographs of scenes from the film.
    - Material for a spy picture, for Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation. n.p., 1936-1937.; 43 leaves. Typescript. (Box 29, Folder 9)
      Included are letters, notes, outline material and various items used in research.
    - Digest of J.W. Hammond's Biography of Charles Steinmetz, by Anne Herendeen, for possible use as a motion picture story. n.p., February 17, 1939.; 33 leaves. Typescript (carbon), fastened in a blue paper cover. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Story reports for motion pictures, for Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation. [Beverly Hills], 1932-1944.; 56 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Izard, Forest - Story ideas for motion pictures, and letters to Kenneth Macgowan. New York, 1930-1932.; 48 leaves. Typescript (much carbon). There is no note as to whether these ideas were carried out. (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Story costs, lists, for RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated. Los Angeles, 1931-1932.; 3 items. Typescript (much carbon) and photocopy. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and John Hay Whitney, mainly concerning color motion pictures, with particular reference to Becky Sharp, and La Cucaracha. v.p., 1933-1934.; 120 leaves. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and John Hay Whitney... continued. v.p., October 1934 - 1935.; 104 leaves. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - General correspondence and records re RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated. v.p., 1932-1935.; 44 items. Typescript (much carbon) and printed material. All items are arranged chronologically. (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Daily bulletins of activities for RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated. [Los Angeles], 1933-1935.; 6 items. Printed (possibly mimeograph). (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Synopsis, tentative treatment, of the screenplay Anne Severn and the Fieldings, by May Sinclair, adapted by Ralph Block, for RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated. n.p., March 7, 1933.; 16 leaves. Typescript, fastened in a blue paper cover. Not known if followed through. (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Synopsis of a screenplay Prelude to Love, by Ralph Block, based on a novel by May Sinclair, for RKO Radio Pictures. n.p., March 17, 1933.; 21 leaves. Typescript (carbon), fastened in a blue paper cover. Not known if followed through. (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Broadcast, a radio interview with Kenneth Macgowan re his role as a motion picture producer. n.p., July 11, 1935.; 6 leaves. Typescript (carbon). Noted in red is BIGG. Perhaps this is the abbreviation for the radio station. (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence re a proposed motion picture about Dr. Bethune for Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation. v.p., 1943.; 71 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, black and white, and miscellaneous research material re a proposed motion picture about Dr. Bethune. n.p., 1943.; 35 items. Typescript (some carbon) and photograph. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Silence, Please! (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and John McNulty of Paramount Studios, Incorporated re a proposed script, Silence Please! for a motion picture. v.p., 1945.; 14 leaves. Holograph and typescript (much carbon). (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sins of Man, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Material re the motion pictures. (Box 30, Folder 4)
        Includes some inter-office correspondence, clippings from newspapers and periodicals, photocopies of drawings of sets, black and white photographs of scenes, plus miscellaneous records of staff, and costs, etc.
    - Stanley and Livingston, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Transcript of conferences with Mr. Zanuck about the story treatment and script for the motion picture. n.p., 1937-1939.; Approximately 150 leaves. Typescript (much carbon), fastened in a blue paper cover. (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence and various records re the motion picture. v.p., 1937-1939.; 122 leaves. Holograph and typescript (much carbon). (Box 30, Folder 6)
        Included are a few letters from Osa Johnson and 1 letter from Henry Stanley Livingston, a grand nephew of Dr. David Livingston. All items are chronologically arranged, with the various records at the back of the folder.
      - Ephemera re the motion picture. v.p., 1938-1939.; 32 items. Printed material. (Box 30, Folder 7)
        Including clippings from newspapers and periodicals, and advertising material.
      - Photographs. Africa, 1937-1939.; 70 items. Black and white, of various sizes, most of them, 8 × 10. (Box 30, Folder 8)
        Includes miscellaneous snapshots, African stills, pictures of scenes, and photocopies of drawings of scenes and sets for the motion picture.
    - Stardust, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1939-1940.; 21 items. Typescript (few carbon), and printed material. (Box 30, Folder 9)
        Including some correspondence, newspaper clippings, and transcripts of conferences about the story.
    - Susannah of the Mounties, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Material re the motion picture. n.p., 1939.; 18 items. Typescript, photocopy, printed, and photograph. (Box 30, Folder 10)
        Including some inter-studio correspondence, various production records, 2 clippings, and black and white photographs of scenes from the film.
    - Swanee River, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1934-1940.; 47 items. Typescript (some carbon), photocopy, and printer items. (Box 30, Folder 11)
        Including some correspondence, production records, story treatment, clippings and a brochure.
    - Anne of Green Gables, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1934.; 28 items. Holograph, typescript (some carbon), printed and photograph. (Box 31, Folder 1)
        Including some correspondence, clippings, black and white photographs, production records, script analysis, and various other material.
    - Becky Sharp, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Clippings from newspapers and periodicals about the motion picture, and color movies. v.p., 1934-1935.; 62 items. (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence and financial records re the motion picture. v.p., 1934-1935.; 25 items. Typescript (some carbon), and photocopy. (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous material re the motion picture. v.p., 1934-1935.; 13 items. Typescript (carbon), mimeograph and photograph. (Box 31, Folder 4)
        Including reviews, comments and various production records, plus a few photographs of scenes.
      - Souvenir and advertising booklets for the motion picture, and for the play. v.p., 1899 and 1935.; 3 items. Printed material. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - La Cucaracha, Pioneer Pictures Production, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Advertising material. v.p., 1934-1935.; 27 items. Typescript (carbon) and printed material. (Box 31, Folder 6)
        Including clippings, and comments re the motion picture.
      - Correspondence and financial records re the film. v.p., 1934-1935.; 11 items. Typescript (few carbon) and photocopy. (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Drawings, and 1 black and white photograph re various phases of production of the film. n.p., 1934-1935.; 23 items. Pencil, ink, and watercolor, and photograph. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous material re color movies, with some reference to Becky Sharp, and La Cucaracha. v.p., 1935-1959.; 16 items. Typescript (some carbon), photocopy and printed material. (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Included are clippings, articles, an interview, plus some correspondence.
    - Hat, Coat and Glove, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1933-1934.; 20 items. Typescript (mostly carbon), printed and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 1)
        Including some inter-studio department correspondence, typescripts of preview card comments, budget reports, clippings, and black and white photographs of scenes from the film.
    - Double Harness, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1933.; 23 items. Printed, photocopy and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 2)
        Including clippings, black and white photographs of scenes, various production records, etc.
    - Enchanted April, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1934.; 13 items. Typescript (some carbon), printed, photocopy and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 3)
        Including typescripts of review postcard comments, various production records, clippings, and black and white photographs of scenes, etc.
    - Finishing School, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Material re the motion picture. [Hollywood], 1934.; 12 items. Typescript (carbon), mimeograph, photocopy, and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 4)
        Including preview postcard comments, budget records, and black and white photographs.
    - The Great Jasper, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Material re the motion picture. [Hollywood], 1932-1933.; 16 items. Typescript (some carbon), photocopy and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 5)
        Including interstudio department communications, budget records, and black and white photographs.
    - If I Were Free, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Material re the motion picture, with the previous title of Behind We Live. Items include inter-studio department memos, various records, and black and white photographs. [Los Angeles], 1933.; 10 items. Typescript (carbon), photocopy and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - I'll Give A Million, Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Material re the motion picture. [Los Angeles], 1938.; 31 items. Printed material, photocopy and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 7)
        Including clippings, photographs, various production records, and a picture estimate.
    - Jalna, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1935.; 43 items. Typescript (carbon), printed, and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 8)
        Including correspondence, clippings, typescripts of review comments, and photographs.
    - Little Women, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence re the motion picture. v.p., 1932-1935.; 40 leaves. Holograph and typescript (some carbon), plus 2 ephemera. Items are filed chronologically. (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous records and papers re the motion picture. [Los Angeles], 1933.; 4 items. Typescript (carbon), and photocopy. (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Pamphlets, clippings, and advertising material re the motion picture. v.p., ca. 1933-1934.; 31 items. Printed material. (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - Photographs of scenes and other subjects re the motion picture. [Hollywood], 1933.; 31 items. Black and white, size 8 × 10. (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Sumurun, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence and story material re the motion picture. v.p., 1934-1935.; 28 items. Typescript (mostly carbon). (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Topaze, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1932-1933.; 16 items. Printed material and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 14)
        Including pamphlets, clippings, and photographs.
    - Wendesday's Child, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1934.; 17 items. Typescript (carbon), printed, and photograph. (Box 32, Folder 15)
        Including clippings and photographs.
    - In Old Chicago, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and other material re the motion picture. v.p., 1936-1937.; 53 items. Typescript (mostly carbon). (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - In Old Chicago. (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Clippings and advertisements for the motion picture. v.p., 1937-1938.; 32 items. Printed. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of drawings for scenes for the motion picture In Old Chicago. Hollywood, 1937.; 34 items. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - In Old Chicago. (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Photographs of scenes from the motion picture and re the motion picture. Hollywood, 1937.; 46 items. (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Souvenir booklets for the movie. n.p., 1937.; 3 items. Printed. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Jane Eyre, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1942-1944.; 13 items. Printed. (Box 33, Folder 6)
        Including clippings, correspondence, and picture estimate.
    - Kentucky Moonshine, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1938.; 23 items. Printed material and photograph. (Box 33, Folder 7)
        Including clippings, photographs, and production materials.
    - Kidnapped, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1936-1938.; 25 items. Mostly printed. (Box 33, Folder 8)
        Including advertisements, correspondence, and ephemera.
      - Photographs of scenes and sets of the motion picture. Hollywood, 1938.; 24 items. Black and white. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Kidnapped. (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Photocopies of drawings of scenes from the motion picture. Hollywood, 1938.; 54 items. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - King of Burlesque, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1935-1936.; 22 items. Typescript (carbon) and printed. (Box 33, Folder 11)
        Including correspondence and advertising materials.
      - Picture estimate for the motion picture. Los Angeles, 1935.; 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Children of Darkness, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence re the proposed motion picture. v.p., 1934-1935.; 12 leaves. Typescript. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence re the motion picture. v.p., 1932-1934.; 97 leaves. Typescript (mostly carbon). (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Hamlet, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1935.; 83 items. Typescript (carbon) and drawing. (Box 34, Folder 3)
        Including correspondence, parts of the script, and set drawings.
    - Long Lost Father, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Material re the motion picture including photographs, correspondence, and production notes. v.p., 1933-1934.; 14 items. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Murder on a Honeymoon, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Material re the motion picture including photographs, ephemera and correspondence. v.p., 1934-1935.; 13 items. Printed, typescript and photograph. (Box 34, Folder 5)